H. David Kaplan Performing Arts Collection
University of Houston Libraries
H. David Kaplan Performing Arts Collection
1940-1996
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
Kaplan, H. David
13.00 Boxes
The H. David Kaplan Performing Arts Collection contains correspondence, publicity photographs, snapshots, slides, programs, various arts publications, autographs, ticket stubs, clippings, posters, showcards, and artwork. The collection is derived from the personal collection of H. David Kaplan.
1986-001
Biographical Note
H. David Kaplan was born in Brooklyn, New York on November 13, 1934. In 1956, he received a B.A. in journalism from The University of Michigan. Kaplan has worked for newspapers, magazines, and corporate communications while also functioning as a patron of and volunteer to the arts throughout the United States.
Kaplan's longstanding interest in the performing/fine arts was established by his parents, and was further entrenched when he lived in New York City. Another influence on his interest in the arts was his uncle, Al Kaplan, who performed in vaudeville throughout the world from 1920-1947.
Kaplan has provided many years of service to the arts through his involvement with the Houston Grand Opera, in his former role as Associate Publisher for Houston's Performing Arts Magazine, and in his ongoing role as an instructor in Enjoying Opera and American Opera courses for continuing education classes in Federal Way, Washington. He has also enhanced the arts collections of several libraries, donating this collection as well as portions of the Hoblitzelle Theatre Collection to the University of Texas, Austin, and a 48-volume collection of New York City theatre playbills and programs to the University of Washington Libraries Special Collections. He continues his enthusiastic patronage of the arts, and routinely donates New York theater programs to libraries and archives.
Scope and Contents
The H. David Kaplan Performing Arts Collection contains correspondence, publicity photographs, photographs taken by Kaplan, programs, various arts publications, autographs and miscellaneous items such as ticket stubs and clippings. There are more than 1,000 color 35 mm. slides taken by Kaplan of opera performances and rehearsals by Houston Grand Opera. Additional oversized collages, posters, showcards, and artwork, along with several framed items, are housed separately. A large part of the collection is signed and many items are personally inscribed to H. David Kaplan. The materials are dated from ca. 1950 to ca. 1996, with the bulk of the collection dating from 1975-1985.
The collection has been retained in the order in which it was received from Mr. Kaplan and, with some modifications; it has been divided into several series. The series are arranged in the different areas of the arts in which Mr. Kaplan was involved or interested and an oversize/framed series which includes every aspect of the arts. Each series may be subdivided into 1-5 subsections including: correspondence, photographs, programs/publications, autographs, and miscellaneous. For ease of storage, the oversize and framed portions of this collection have been placed together in a series and shelved separately.
Correspondence has been separated and is organized alphabetically by the last name of the correspondent. Copies of H. David Kaplan's letters to individual correspondents are filed with their replies. In publicity photographs, the production, if known, has been noted on the reverse side in pencil.
Bound volumes of Performing Arts Magazine, Houston Arts Magazine, Tonight and Houston on Stage donated by Mr. Kaplan have been incorporated into the library's holdings. These may be found by searching the UH Libraries' catalog by journal title or by author, using the phrase "H. David Kaplan Performing Arts Collection."
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Ballet programs; Memorabilia; Newsletters; Pamphlets; Postcards; Scrapbooks; Slides; Theater programs
Topical Term:
Art patrons; Pictorial works.; Playbills; Souvenirs (Keepsakes); Symphony orchestras
Access Restrictions
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Detailed Description
- Correspondence 1974-1987
  Organized alphabetically by last name of correspondent; includes Christmas cards, personal notes, opera companies in Texas, U.S., invitations and magazine submissions.
  - Incoming Correspondence, A-M (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Incoming Correspondence, M-Z (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Outgoing Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Opera, 1970s-1980s
  The largest concentration in Kaplan's collection is devoted to Opera. The bulk of this series are autographed memorabilia, posters, articles, and performances related to Houston Grand Opera. Smaller sub-series include fliers, scripts, programs and schedules for Houston Grand Opera and other Texas and national opera companies. There are several folders with 35 mm. slides from Houston Grand Opera rehearsals and performances.
  - Autographed Memorabilia, 1971-1980, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Autographed Memorabilia, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Autographed Memorabilia, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Autographed Memorabilia, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Fliers (Box 1)
    - Dallas Civic Opera (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Fort Worth Opera (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Houston Grand Opera (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Houston Grand Opera (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Houston Opera Studio (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Lyric Opera (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Metropolitan Opera, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - New Orleans, 1972-1981 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - San Antonio (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - San Francisco, 1973-81, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Tacoma Pierce County Opera (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Texas Opera Theater (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Tulsa Performing Arts, 1980-83 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Invitations (Box 1)
    - Invitations, 1976-1986 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Invitations, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Librettos (Box 1)
    - I Capuleti e i Montecchi (The Capulets and The Montagues) (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - A Quiet Place/Pique Dame/ Curlew River (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Tancredi (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - News clippings (Box 1)
    - News clippings (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - News clippings (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - News clippings (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - News clippings (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - News clippings (Box 2)
    - News clippings, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - News clippings, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - News clippings, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - News clippings, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - News clippings, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - News clippings, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - News clippings, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - News clippings: New Orleans (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - News clippings: Tulsa Opera (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Periodicals (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous, 1971-82 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Seattle Opera, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Photographs (Box 2)
    - Photographic Materials, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Photographic Materials, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Photographic Materials, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Photographic Materials, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Postcards (Box 2)
    - Singers of the Metropolitan Opera House (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Posters (Box 2)
    - Posters, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Posters, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Press Materials (Box 2)
    - Dallas Opera, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous, 1980s (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Programs (Box 2)
    - Dallas Civic Opera, 1967-75 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Dallas Civic Opera, 1973-77 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Houston Grand Opera, 1956-62 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Houston Grand Opera, 1963-1969 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Programs (Box 3)
    - Houston Grand Opera, 1966-67 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Houston Grand Opera, 1968-69 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Houston Grand Opera, 1970-71 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Houston Grand Opera, 1972-79 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Houston Grand Opera, 1980-86 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Houston On Stage, October 1984-April 1985 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Jones Hall, 1966-71 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Lyric at 25 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Lyric Opera of Chicago, 1972-80 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Lyric Opera of Kansas City, 1977 and 1982 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Metropolitan Grand Opera Dallas, 1946-56 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Metropolitan Opera Dallas, 1970-72 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Metropolitan Opera House, 1953 and 1976 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - New Orleans Opera Association, 1968-82 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Opera Cues, 1972-75 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Opera Cues, 1976-77 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Opera Cues, 1977-82 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Performing Arts, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Playbill: Music Hall Dallas (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - San Antonio Grand Opera, 1945-76 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - San Francisco Opera, 1977-85 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Programs (Box 4)
    - Shreveport Civic Opera, 1969-70 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Society for the Performing Arts (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Society for the Performing Arts (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Texas Opera Theater, 1974-84 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Tulsa, 1974-78 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Opera, 1982-83 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 1929-67 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 1975-85 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Public Service Announcement (Box 4)
    - Texas Opera Theater (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Radio Broadcast (Box 4)
    - Houston Grand Opera (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Schedules (Box 4)
    - Catherine Malfitano 1994 Itinerary (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Houston Grand Opera, 1971-88 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Indiana University, 1972-73 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Jones Hall, 1966, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Metropolitan in Dallas (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - San Diego Opera, 1980-81 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - San Francisco Opera, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Seattle Opera, 1981-87 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Texas Opera Theater, 1977-82 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Printed Materials (Box 4)
    - Houston Grand Opera, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Houston Grand Opera, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Texas Opera Theater, 1980s (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Slides (Box 4)
    Photographic slides taken by H. David Kaplan during Houston Grand Opera and Texas Opera Theater rehearsals and performances.
    - Texas Opera Theater and Houston Grand Opera 1980 National Radio Broadcasts (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Houston Grand Opera (Box 4, Folder 25)
      - Turandot, 1969; The Ballad of Baby Doe, 1970; Aida, 1971; Lucia di Lammermoor, 1971; Boris Godonuv, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 25, Item 1)
      - Tannhauser, April 1972 (Box 4, Folder 25, Item 2)
      - The Elixir of Love, May 1972 (Box 4, Folder 25, Item 3)
      - Susannah, May 1972; Susannah, May 1972; Floyd/Bachann, May 1972 (Box 4, Folder 25, Item 4)
      - Madame Butterfly, October 1972 (Box 4, Folder 25, Item 5)
      - The Daughter of the Regiment (Box 4, Folder 25, Item 6)
      - The Daughter of the Regiment (Box 4, Folder 25, Item 7)
      - Of Mice and Men, Feb. 1973; L'histoire du Soldat, June 1973; The Impresario, June 1973; Hugh the Drover, June 1973 (Box 4, Folder 25, Item 8)
      - La Rondine, June 1973 (Box 4, Folder 25, Item 9)
    - Houston Grand Opera (Box 4, Folder 26)
      - Macbeth, Oct. 1973 (Box 4, Folder 26, Item 10)
      - The Marriage of Figaro, Nov. 1973 (Box 4, Folder 26, Item 11)
      - The Marriage of Figaro, Nov. 1973 (Box 4, Folder 26, Item 12)
      - The Marriage of Figaro, Nov. 1973; La Traviata, Jan. 1974 (Box 4, Folder 26, Item 13)
      - La Traviata, Jan. 1974 (Box 4, Folder 26, Item 14)
      - La Traviata, Jan. 1974; The Seagull, March 1974 (Box 4, Folder 26, Item 15)
      - The Seagull, March 1974 (Box 4, Folder 26, Item 16)
      - The Seagull, March 1974 (Box 4, Folder 26, Item 17)
      - La Perichole, March 1974 (Box 4, Folder 26, Item 18)
      - La Perichole, March 1974 (Box 4, Folder 26, Item 19)
    - Houston Grand Opera (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - Mefistofele, April 1974 (Box 4, Folder 27, Item 20)
      - Carmen, May 1974 (Box 4, Folder 27, Item 21)
      - The Abduction from the Seraglio, May 1974 (Box 4, Folder 27, Item 22)
      - The Abduction from the Seraglio, May 1974; McDonald/Robinson/Ley; TV-CN.26; Threepenny Opera (Box 4, Folder 27, Item 23)
      - The Threepenny Opera, June 1974; The Rise and Fall of the City of Mahagonny, March 1974 (Box 4, Folder 27, Item 24)
      - The Rise and Fall of the City of Mahagonny, March 1974; Calvary, April 1974 (Box 4, Folder 27, Item 25)
      - Calvary, May 1974 (Box 4, Folder 27, Item 26)
      - Mefistofele Preview/Manon, Oct. 1974 (Box 4, Folder 27, Item 27)
      - Manon, Oct. 1974 (Box 4, Folder 27, Item 28)
      - Il Trovatore, Oct. 1974 (Box 4, Folder 27, Item 29)
      - Il Trovatore, Oct. 1974 (Box 4, Folder 27, Item 30)
    - Houston Grand Opera (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - La Boheme (Box 4, Folder 28, Item 31)
      - La Boheme, Der Rosenkavalier (Box 4, Folder 28, Item 32)
      - Der Rosenkavalier (Box 4, Folder 28, Item 33)
      - Der Rosenkavalier (Box 4, Folder 28, Item 34)
      - Der Rosenkavalier (Box 4, Folder 28, Item 35)
      - Der Rosenkavalier, The Play of Herod, Lucrezia Borgia (Box 4, Folder 28, Item 36)
      - Lucrezia Borgia (Box 4, Folder 28, Item 37)
      - Lucrezia Borgiz, Lulu (Box 4, Folder 28, Item 38)
      - Lulu (Box 4, Folder 28, Item 39)
      - Lulu (Box 4, Folder 28, Item 40)
    - Houston Grand Opera (Box 4, Folder 29)
      - Lulu, Candide, Rinaldo (Box 4, Folder 29, Item 41)
      - Rinaldo (Box 4, Folder 29, Item 42)
      - Treemonisha (Box 4, Folder 29, Item 43)
      - Treemonisha, Lucrezia Borgia (Box 4, Folder 29, Item 44)
      - Lucrezia Borgia, Candide (Box 4, Folder 29, Item 45)
      - Lucrezia Borgia, El Capitan (Box 4, Folder 29, Item 46)
      - El Capitan, Faust (Box 4, Folder 29, Item 47)
      - Faust (Box 4, Folder 29, Item 48)
      - Faust (Box 4, Folder 29, Item 49)
      - Faust, Rinaldo (Box 4, Folder 29, Item 50)
  - Slides (Box 5)
    - (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Rinaldo, Otello (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 51)
      - Otello (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 52)
      - Otello (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 53)
      - Texas Opera Theater: Turn of the Screw, The Barber of Seville, Amahl and the Night Visitors (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 54)
      - Amahl and the Night Visitors, El Capitan (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 55)
      - El Capitan, Don Giovanni (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 56)
      - Don Giovanni (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 57)
      - Don Giovanni, Bilby's Doll (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 58)
      - Bilby's Doll (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 59)
      - Bilby's Doll (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 60)
    - (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - La Fanciulla del West (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 61)
      - La Fanciulla del West, Don Giovanni (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 62)
      - Don Giovanni (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 63)
      - Don Giovanni (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 64)
      - Don Giovanni, Porgy amp;amp; Bess (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 65)
      - Porgy amp;amp; Bess (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 66)
      - Porgy amp;amp; Bess, Susannah (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 67)
      - Susannah (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 68)
      - Susannah (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 69)
      - Susannah, The Barber of Seville (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 70)
    - (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - The Barber of Seville (Box 5, Folder 3, Item 71)
      - The Barber of Seville (Box 5, Folder 3, Item 72)
      - The Barber of Seville, Rigoletto (Box 5, Folder 3, Item 73)
      - Rigoletto (Box 5, Folder 3, Item 74)
      - Rigoletto (Box 5, Folder 3, Item 75)
      - Andrea Chenier (Box 5, Folder 3, Item 76)
      - Andrea Chenier (Box 5, Folder 3, Item 77)
      - Andrea Chenier, Peter Grimes (Box 5, Folder 3, Item 78)
      - Peter Grimes (Box 5, Folder 3, Item 79)
      - Peter Grimes, The Barber of Seville (Box 5, Folder 3, Item 80)
    - (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - The Coronation of Poppea (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 81)
      - The Coronation of Poppea (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 82)
      - The Coronation of Poppea, Andrea Chenier (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 83)
      - Andrea Chenier (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 84)
      - Andrea Chenier, The Daughter of the Regiment (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 85)
      - The Daughter of the Regiment (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 86)
      - The Daughter of the Regiment, Salome (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 87)
      - Salome (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 88)
      - Salome (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 89)
      - Salome, Arabella (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 90)
    - (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Arabella, Tancredi (Box 5, Folder 5, Item 91)
      - Tancredi (Box 5, Folder 5, Item 92)
      - Tancredi, Of Mice and Men (Box 5, Folder 5, Item 93)
      - Of Mice and Men, The Daughter of the Regiment (Box 5, Folder 5, Item 94)
      - The Daughter of the Regiment, Aida (Box 5, Folder 5, Item 95)
      - Aida, Robinson Crusoe (Box 5, Folder 5, Item 96)
      - Robinson Crusoe (Box 5, Folder 5, Item 97)
      - Robinson Crusoe, Arabella (Box 5, Folder 5, Item 98)
      - Arabella (Box 5, Folder 5, Item 99)
      - Arabella, Tosca (Box 5, Folder 5, Item 100)
    - (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Tosca (Box 5, Folder 6, Item 101)
      - Tosca, The Merry Widow (Box 5, Folder 6, Item 102)
      - The Merry Widow (Box 5, Folder 6, Item 103)
      - The Merry Widow (Box 5, Folder 6, Item 104)
      - The Merry Widow (Box 5, Folder 6, Item 105)
      - Hansel amp;amp; Gretel (Box 5, Folder 6, Item 106)
      - Hansel amp;amp; Gretel, Madame Butterfly (Box 5, Folder 6, Item 107)
      - Madame Butterfly (Box 5, Folder 6, Item 108)
      - Madame Butterfly (Box 5, Folder 6, Item 109)
      - Madame Butterfly, Tosca (Box 5, Folder 6, Item 110)
    - (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Tosca, Jenufa (Box 5, Folder 7, Item 111)
      - Jenufa (Box 5, Folder 7, Item 112)
      - Jenufa, Norma (Box 5, Folder 7, Item 113)
      - Norma (Box 5, Folder 7, Item 114)
      - Norma, Hansel amp;amp; Gretel (Box 5, Folder 7, Item 115)
      - Hansel amp;amp; Gretel, Werther (Box 5, Folder 7, Item 116)
      - Werther (Box 5, Folder 7, Item 117)
      - Werther (Box 5, Folder 7, Item 118)
      - Werther, Texas Opera Theater: The Marriage of Figaro (Box 5, Folder 7, Item 119)
      - TOT: Figaro, Jenufa (Box 5, Folder 7, Item 120)
      - Jenufa (Box 5, Folder 7, Item 121)
- Dance, 1970s-1980s
  The bulk of this series is made up of printed materials: fliers, invitations, news clippings, articles, posters and programs, as well as photographs primarily of Houston Ballet and other national dance companies.
  - Autographed Memorabilia (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Fliers: Houston Ballet Newsletter, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Fliers: Houston Ballet, 1978-82 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Fliers: Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Invitations (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - News clippings, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - News clippings, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - News clippings, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Periodicals (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Periodicals (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Photographic Materials (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Posters (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Press Releases (Box 6)
    - Houston Ballet, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Joffrey Ballet, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Programs (Box 6)
    - American Ballet Theatre 35th Anniversary, 1974-75 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Houston Ballet, 1972-1984 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Houston Ballet Season Repertory Programs, 1977-86 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Houston Ballet Academy, 1979-82 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Houston Ballet Orchestra, 1984-86 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Joffrey Ballet (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Jones Hall, October, 1973, February 1974, December 1983 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - New York City Ballet, 1964, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Sadler's Wells/Royal Ballet, 1950-69 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Society for the Performing Arts, 1970s (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous, 1953-1986, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Schedules (Box 6)
    - Schedules, 1970s (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Schedules, 1980s (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Schedules, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Instrumental, 1960s-1980s
  The bulk of this series is made up of printed materials: fliers, invitations, news clippings, programs and schedules, as well as photographs relating to Houston Symphony, regional and national orchestras.
  - Autographed Memorabilia (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Fliers (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Invitations, 1981-1984, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - News clippings, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Photographic Materials (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Programs (Box 6)
    - The Houston Chamber Orchestra Society, September 1967-February 1976 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Houston Civic Music Association, November 1968-April 1974 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Houston Symphony Orechestra, 1969-1983 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Los Angeles Philharmonic (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Minnesota Orchestra, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - San Francisco Symphony, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - San Francisco Symphony: Inaugural Week, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Society for the Performing Arts, 1967-1976 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Symphony, May 1978-December 1983 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Texas Chamber Orchestra, 1980-1984 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 33)
- Theatre, 1960s-1980s
  The bulk of this series is made up of printed materials: fliers, invitations, news clippings, and programs, for Houston (Chocolate Bayou Theatre, Alley Theatre, University of Houston, etc.) and regional theaters in the U.S.
  - Autographed Memorabilia (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Fliers (Box 6)
    - The Alley Theatre, 1975-84 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Miscellaneous, 1972-87, undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Invitations, 1982-84 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - News clippings (Box 7)
    - News clippings, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - News clippings, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - News clippings, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - News clippings, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters (Box 7)
    - The Alley Theatre Marquee, 1982-86 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Chocolatier, 1984-86 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Photographic Materials (Box 7)
    - (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Postcards (Box 7)
    - Folger Shakespeare Library (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Press Release (Box 7)
    - Stages, 1981/82 Season (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Programs (Box 7)
    - The Alley, 1967-69 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - The Alley, 1971-78 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - The Alley, 1980-82 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Channing Players, 1971, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Chocolate Bayou Theatre, 1980-84 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - College on the Mainland Community Theatre, 1979-81 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - The Comedy Workshop, 1981-82 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - The Country Playhouse, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Equinox Theatre, 1980-81 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Gilbert and Sullivan Society, 1968-1979 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Guthrie Theater, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Holiday Dinner Theatre, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Houston Music Theatre, 1968-72 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Main Street Theatre, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Palo Duro Canyon State Park: "Texas", 1975 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Performing Arts, 1985-87 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - The Proscenium 1975-77 Season (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Southwest Theatre Guild, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Stages (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Starlight Operetta, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Theatre Suburbia, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Theatre under the Stars (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Programs (Box 8)
    - Town and Country Dinner Theatre, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - University of Houston, 1978-85 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Windmill Dinner Theatre, 1973, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)